Hello, English learners.
Welcome back to English Todd.
My name is Marco and I'm Erica and today
we're bringing you a great office lesson.
That's right, but actually
I hope this situation
never happens to any
of our listeners. Exactly.
Today we are firing
somebody. It is a little bit
complicated, but maybe
you're a HR manager, maybe
you are a supervisor, and
you'll have to do this one day.
So gotta learn
how, right? Exactly.
All right. Well, why
don't we get started then?
As we listen to Isabelle and Anthony.
Hi Isabelle. You wanted to see me?
Yes, Anthony. Come on in and have a seat.
Is everything okay? You
see him a bit preoccupied.
Well, Anthony, this is not
going to be an easy conversation.
The company has
made some decisions
which will have a direct
impact on your employment.
Okay. I don't want to
beat around the bush, so
I'm just gonna come out
with it. We're gonna have
to let you go. What?
Why? I mean, just like
that, I'm fired? I'm
sorry, but to be honest,
you're a terrible employee.
What? I resent that.
Anthony, you were
caught making international
calls from the office
phone. You called in sick
eight times this month,
and you smell like alcohol.
He did sound a little bit
like he had too much to drink.
I know he had that kind of slur.
Yeah, that that slow way of talking
that made him seem a little bit drunk.
Well, that's definitely
something you don't want to
do is show up to work
with alcohol in your breath.
Exactly, but you know
what? There's a lot of
great language in this
dialogue, so why don't we
take a look at it now
in language takeaway?
Language takeaway. All
right, well, I want to look at
three words here. Now,
the first one, Anthony
said that Isabelle was
preoccupied. Preoccupied.
Preoccupied. Okay, so if
somebody is preoccupied,
they're not focused. Maybe
they're a little bit worried.
Yeah, they're thinking
of something else.
Okay, so why don't
we take a listen to a few
examples of how this
word is used? Example one.
James is really preoccupied.
I think he's having
some family
problems. Example two.
Oh, were you talking to me,
honey? I'm sorry. I'm just really
preoccupied with work.
All right, so very clear
now, preoccupied. Let's
move on to our next word,
direct impact, direct
impact, a direct impact.
All right, so again,
Isabelle told Anthony that
the decision will have a
direct impact on his career.
It will have a noticeable or
impact or effect on his career.
Okay, so a direct impact.
And what about our last word?
Well, Anthony said, I resent that.
Resent. Resent. Okay,
now this is spelled
exactly like recent,
like with an S, right?
That's right, R, E, S, E, and T.
But you pronounce it like a Z.
Resent. Resent
that. So what does it
mean if you say I resent that?
It means I find that insulting.
I find that to be not true. Yes.
Okay, I resent. All right, Marco,
well, how do you use this word?
Well, if somebody
tells you you're lazy.
Okay, right. Then you
might say, hey, I resent that.
Right, I do a lot of
work. I'm not lazy.
Yeah, so it's always
something that you use after
someone insults you.
Right. Or says something
that you find to be not
true. Okay, resent that.
And I guess with this,
it's time for us to listen
to this dialogue again. And then we'll
come back and look at some great phrases.
Hey, Isabel, you wanted
to see me? Yes, Anthony,
come on in and have a
seat. Is everything okay?
You see him a bit
preoccupied. Well, Anthony,
this is not going to be
an easy conversation.
The company has made
some decisions, which will
have a direct impact on
your employment. Okay.
I don't want to beat
around the bush.
So I'm just going to come out
with it. We're going to have to
let you go. What?
Why? I mean, just like
that, I'm fired. I'm
sorry, but to be honest,
you're a terrible employee.
What? I resent that.
Anthony, you were
caught making international
calls from the office
phone. You called in sick
eight times this month
and you smell like alcohol.
You know, there's some
wonderful language in
here that you can use
when you have to have
a difficult conversation
with somebody. Right.
So let's take a look at
these phrases in fluency
builder. Fluency builder.
We have three phrases here.
And the first one is to
beat around the bush.
Okay, beat around the bush. Beat around the
bush. Okay. So this is an idiomatic phrase.
So before we explain it, let's listen to
somebody beating around the bush.
Okay. The one thing
that I want to tell you,
um, it's so important
that I don't like they,
I always sometimes when,
all right, here's a deal.
This is it. Specifically,
it's not this.
It's not that it's
not you. It's not me.
It's everyone. It's everything.
Do you understand what I'm
saying? So as you can tell,
the person has something
to say, but they're taking
a long time to say it.
Right. You're kind of
looking for the right
or maybe more polite
words to say something.
Exactly. So that is to
beat around the bush.
Now the opposite of to
beat around the bush is to
come out with it.
Okay. Come out with it.
Come out with it. So maybe
you're talking to your friend and
he's beating around the
bush. So you can just say, Hey,
come out with it. Tell
me. Tell me. Just what is it?
Exactly. Right. Come
out with it. Be direct.
When Isabel finally came
out with it, she told Anthony
that we're going to
have to let you go.
Let you go. Let you go. So
this is actually a nicer way of
saying you're fired.
Yeah. It's a little bit more
polite, isn't it? Right.
It's we're going to have
to let you go or oh, I was
let go from my company.
Right. So a synonym
for to be fired.
Exactly. Okay. So let's listen to
Anthony getting fired one more time.
And then we'll come back and talk a little
bit more about this difficult situation.
Hi Isabel. You wanted to see me?
Yes, Anthony. Come on in and have a seat.
Is everything okay? You
see him a bit preoccupied?
Well, Anthony, this
is not going to be an
easy conversation. The
company has made some
decisions, which will have a
direct impact on your employment.
Okay. I don't want to
beat around the bush.
So I'm just going
to come out with it.
We're going to have to
let you go. What? Why?
I mean, just like that,
I'm fired. I'm sorry, but
to be honest, you're a
terrible employee. What?
I resent that. Anthony,
you were caught making
international calls
from the office phone.
You called in sick eight
times this month and
you smell like alcohol. So Erica,
have you ever fired anyone?
I have fired a lot of people.
Oh, wow. You are a
mean person. Oh, yeah.
Well, you know, there
are some people who really
do silly things like
come to work drunk.
And if you do that, you're
obviously going to get fired.
Yeah. But in the
United States, actually,
there is an interesting
way of firing people.
They get a pink slip. Oh, yeah.
But I guess this is just a little
bit different than getting fired.
This is you get a pink
slip when you get laid off.
Right. Yep. I mean, if you come to work
a drunk, you get fired immediately, right?
But when you get a
pink slip, so it's basically a
little pink paper that tells
you that you have been laid off.
Yeah. And so when
you hear somebody say,
we send out, yeah, so when
you hear somebody talk
about pink slips, like we
send like our company
sent out 500 pink slips,
you know that means
that 500 people got laid
off or I got a pink slip today.
That means you got
laid off. Right. Yep.
That's actually interesting
because I don't know
any other country that
actually has this special
color, special color
for firing people. Yeah.
How about in your
country, is there a special
color for pink slips?
If you guys have any
stories as well, maybe
about being fired or maybe
you've had to fire somebody,
come to our website
and tell us about it.
Right. EnglishPod.com.
There you can leave your
questions and comments.
Eric and I are always
there trying to answer your
questions and also our
great community is there.
They will also help
you. Okay, guys.
Well, we're out of time for
today, but until next time. Bye.